Now that I am satisfied with the content
structure and layout of the presentation.
It's time to start thinking about
adding some additional effects that
will enhance the meaning and appearance
when presented to an audience.
The two tools that I'm going to look
at are transitions and animations.
The first thing the transitions
is quite simply how one slide will
transition  into another slide.
So at the moment, when I click on
slideshow and play the slideshow from the
beginning, the slide appears instantly.
And then as I click each
slide then appears instantly.
So if I press the exit button
and go back to my presentation.
If I select slide one, and then I
go to the transitions tab and select
that, as you can see along the top
there are a range of transition
effects that can be applied.
And just as an example,
I'm going to select split.
So that is the effect that
will be applied to that slide.
You can select different transitions
for different slides but if you are
presenting this to a professional
audience, I would recommend maintaining
consistency within the slides, so
the transition should be the same
and there an easy way of doing that.
So if I select slide one again.
I know that split has
been applied to slide one.
So if I move over to the right and
select the apply to all button,
that has then applied that same
transition effect to all of the slides.
So if I go to slideshow and play that now.
Every time I click each slide
will transition in with the
effect that I have applied.
So once I'm happy with the
transitions, I can then think about
adding some animation effects.
So animation effects can be
applied to different sections and
elements within your presentation.
So to access the animations, I need
to click on the animations tab.
As you can see, along the top, all of the
animation effects are currently greyed out
they will not become active until I select
an element within a slide to animate.
But as soon as I click into the text
box there they all become active.
And again, as with the transitions, you
can click each one and it will apply
that effect to the selected element.
And when you're satisfied with the
one that you wish to use and I'm
going to select grow and turn for
that element there, and then I'm going
to apply some animation to the two
images and the other element of text.
So I'll highlight the first image and
I'm going to select fade for that one.
Then I will highlight the second image
and I will select float in for that one.
And finally, I will select
the sales report and I want to
stick with the grow and turn.
So that is consistent
with the text at the top.
So now I've applied four
animation effects to that slide.
So if I played that now go to slideshow
and selected from beginning it
transitions in, and if I click, the
first element appears I click again,
the second element and again and again.
When I click again, the only
thing I have set up on the
other slides are transitions.
So there's no animation effects yet.
So it would just transition
through each of those.
So once I'm  satisfied with the
animations on slide one, I can then go
on to slide two, three, four, and five,
and add animation effects to those.
And there are some other features
within the animations that you can use
to delay and enhance the animations,
which will be covered in session six.